All right.
好的。
So we've talked about quite a few quantifiable so far we've got still some more to go.
因此，到目前为止，我们已经讨论了很多可量化的内容，我们还有更多内容要做。
These are all really really common.
这些都很常见。
I want to be clear that there are others we're not talking about every single one that's out there.
我想明确一点，我们并不是在谈论其他的每一个。
We're talking about the ones that are very common and how to use them.
我们正在谈论那些非常常见的以及如何使用它们。
Now let's go on to many and some and I realize that you probably know pretty much all of these but it's
现在让我们继续讨论很多，我意识到你可能知道几乎所有这些，但它是
got to be really really clear when you should use them.
必须非常清楚何时应该使用它们。
So I just want to make sure we have this very important important lesson to brush up on the basics.
所以我只想确保我们有这个非常重要的课程来复习基础知识。
So many many as you probably know is for things that are countable like people like dreams like cups.
你可能知道的很多东西都是为了可数的东西，比如人，比如梦，比如杯子。
And some can be used for both.
有些可以同时用于两者。
Very similar to a lot I would say that a lot and some are exact opposites.
与很多非常相似，我会说很多，有些是完全相反的。
A general rule you can follow is if you want to say a large amount and you're not sure which word to
您可以遵循的一般规则是，如果您想说很多并且不确定该说哪个词
use because you are thinking about is it countable or or uncountable.
使用，因为您正在考虑它是可数的还是不可数的。
Well if it's a large amount use a lot.
好吧，如果它是大量使用很多。
If it's a small amount use some.
如果是少量，请使用一些。
It's a great one because you don't have to think about which type of noun to use it with.
这是一个很棒的词，因为您不必考虑与哪种名词一起使用。
So let's look at some examples of many first.
因此，让我们首先看一些例子。
I've got many awards in my office.
我的办公室里有很多奖项。
What kind of person is this.
这是一个什么样的人。
Who says this.
谁说这个。
I've got many awards in my office.
我的办公室里有很多奖项。
Awards are things that you get if you do something well.
奖励是你做得好的事情。
This person is talking about their awards.
这个人正在谈论他们的奖项。
I don't like this person bragging a little bit maybe showing off showing off a bit showing off anyway
我不喜欢这个人有点吹牛可能会炫耀 反正有点炫耀
they've got many awards could we say many time.
他们获得了很多奖项，我们可以说很多次。
No we cannot say many times if we're using time as accountable thing.
不，如果我们将时间用作负责的事情，我们不能说很多次。
Like one time two times three times that I've been to Canada.
就像我去过加拿大一次两次三次一样。
OK.
好的。
But now we could not say many time the general idea time.
但是现在我们不能说很多时间的一般概念时间。
We could not say many hope.
我们不能说很多希望。
We could not say many milk for example say bottles of milk cups of milk grains of rice many grains of
我们不能说很多牛奶 例如说几瓶牛奶 杯子 牛奶 米粒 很多粒
rice.
白饭。
But we cannot use any milk.
但是我们不能使用任何牛奶。
OK.
好的。
There are so many buttons.
有这么多按钮。
I'm confused.
我很困惑。
OK.
好的。
Person is looking at a panel has a lot of buttons on it.
人正在看一个面板上有很多按钮。
Which one do I push so many buttons.
我要按哪一个按钮这么多。
We can count buttons.
我们可以数按钮。
So it works.
所以它有效。
So it works for the last two examples of many.
所以它适用于最后两个例子。
Let's look at some common idioms idioms are expressions that pretty much everybody knows.
让我们来看看一些常见的成语 成语是几乎每个人都知道的表达方式。
And you have to say them as is OK.
你必须说他们没问题。
Too many cooks in the kitchen spoil the broth and the broth is for example a soup.
厨房里太多的厨师会破坏肉汤，而肉汤就是汤。
And if you have a kitchen and there are many cooks working in that kitchen the idea is if there are
如果你有一个厨房并且有很多厨师在那个厨房工作，那么这个想法就是如果有
five or six of them all working on the same thing it's going to turn out bad.
他们中的五六个人都在做同样的事情，结果会很糟糕。
Maybe they didn't communicate well one person puts in Salt another person comes in puts in more salt
也许他们没有很好地沟通一个人放盐另一个人进来放更多盐
but they didn't tell that person.
但他们没有告诉那个人。
So now it's too salty.
所以现在太咸了。
So it's better if you have one person in control.
所以最好有一个人来控制。
Sometimes it's better to have fewer people because then whatever you're doing is more focused and there's
有时人少会更好，因为这样无论你在做什么，都会更加专注，而且
great communication there's a clear direction.
良好的沟通有一个明确的方向。
Many people communicating too many cooks spoil the broth.
许多人交流太多厨师会破坏肉汤。
Means you're going to ruin whatever you're doing.
意味着你会毁掉你正在做的任何事情。
If there are too many people involved.
如果涉及的人太多。
Very common.
很常见。
There are many ways to skin a cat.
给猫剥皮的方法有很多种。
That means to remove the skin of a cat.
这意味着去除猫的皮肤。
Now that's pretty gross.
现在这很恶心。
That's a pretty disgusting idea.
这是一个非常恶心的想法。
But it's a common expression which basically means our goal is to do this but there isn't only one way
但这是一个常见的表达方式，基本上意味着我们的目标是做到这一点，但方法不止一种
to get there.
到那里。
We're trying to get a million users.
我们正在努力获得一百万用户。
Well there are many different ways to get a million users.
那么有很多不同的方式来获得一百万用户。
We could spend a lot of money or maybe we make some very viral videos on the Internet and make a lot
我们可以花很多钱，或者我们在互联网上制作一些非常流行的视频并赚很多钱
of people who see our videos come to look at whatever we're selling.
观看我们视频的人会来看我们销售的任何产品。
And so we can get a million users.
所以我们可以获得一百万用户。
The idea is there isn't only one way to do something.
这个想法是不仅有一种方法可以做某事。
There are many ways to skin a cat.
给猫剥皮的方法有很多种。
Now for some as I mentioned it can be countable or uncountable and it's very similar to a bit in some
现在对于我提到的一些人来说，它可以是可数的也可以是不可数的，它与一些中的一点非常相似
ways because you can use it to be a little understated.
方式，因为你可以用它来有点低调。
So if you say I have I have some suggestions on how to how to improve or how you can improve right I
所以如果你说我有我有一些关于如何改进或如何改进的建议我
am improve improve how to improve well maybe I have many maybe I have quite a few things to say maybe
正在改进 改进 如何改进 或许我有很多 或许我有很多话要说 或许
I'm going to talk for 20 minutes about how to help you improve.
我将用 20 分钟的时间讨论如何帮助您改进。
My feedback will be very long but I say some as a way to make it a little understated.
我的反馈会很长，但我说一些是为了让它有点低调。
Now it's of course possible that it actually is some it actually is a small amount but I just want to
现在当然有可能它实际上是一些它实际上是少量但我只是想
be clear some can be used in the same way as a little and a bit to be understated when actually it's
明确一些可以以相同的方式使用，实际上它有点被低估了
much much more even though the actual meaning of some is a small amount.
即使一些的实际含义是少量的，也要多得多。
OK you need some help with your makeup.
好的，你需要一些化妆方面的帮助。
You need some help with your makeup.
你需要一些帮助来化妆。
OK so someone maybe has put makeup on maybe for a video and there's too much it's done incorrectly.
好的，所以有人可能为视频化妆了，而且做得太多了。
It looks weird.
看起来很奇怪。
So one person makes a comment.
所以一个人发表评论。
You need some help is help countable or uncountable.
你需要一些帮助是可数的或不可数的。
Help is uncountable.
帮助是不可数的。
Help is uncountable it's a general concept so well for example suggestions is countable help is more
帮助是不可数的，这是一个普遍的概念，例如建议是可数的，帮助更多
of an idea more of an abstract thing uncountable but some can be used for both.
一个想法更多的是不可数的抽象事物，但有些可以同时用于两者。
Now I'd like to give you two examples that get across this idea of how we can use a noun either as a
现在我想给你两个例子来理解我们如何使用名词作为
countable thing or an uncountable thing.
可数事物或不可数事物。
Let's get some pizza let's get some pizzas.
让我们吃些比萨饼 让我们吃些比萨饼吧。
What's different about these two.
这两个有什么不同。
Well you can see here that pizzas is now plural and it is countable because we could say a pizza.
好吧，您可以在这里看到比萨饼现在是复数并且是可数的，因为我们可以说比萨饼。
Lets get off pizza or let's get some pizzas.
让我们下比萨饼或让我们得到一些比萨饼。
That means more than one maybe three maybe four and let's get some pizza.
这意味着不止一个，也许三个，也许四个，让我们去买些比萨吧。
Now this is an uncountable.
现在这是一个不可数的。
It's not single it's an uncountable noun.
它不是单一的，它是一个不可数名词。
It's being used as a concept pizza can be uncountable as well.
它被用作概念比萨饼也可以是不可数的。
Now this sum also works.
现在这个总和也有效。
It still works if we say for example let's get a few a few pizzas then we can't say let's get a few
如果我们说让我们买几个比萨饼，它仍然有效，然后我们不能说让我们买几个
pizza.
比萨。
That doesn't work because a few can only be used for countable things but some works for both because
那是行不通的，因为一些只能用于可数的事情，但有些则适用于两者，因为
some works for both.
有些适用于两者。
So it's pretty great.
所以它非常棒。
We could say let's get let's get pizza.
我们可以说让我们吃披萨。
We can take this some out and then once again if we say let's get pizza it can still be uncountable.
我们可以把它拿出来，然后再一次，如果我们说让我们吃披萨，它仍然是不可数的。
We could say let's get a lot of pizza.
我们可以说让我们买很多披萨。
It's uncountable.
是不可数的。
Last example give it some time.
最后一个例子给它一些时间。
It will work out just fine.
它会很好的。
Give it some time.
给它一些时间。
Time countable or uncountable.
时间可数或不可数。
It is uncountable.
这是不可数的。
In this case again it can be countable.
在这种情况下，它又可以是可数的。
We could say I've been there a few times sometimes.
我们可以说我有时去过那里几次。
Maybe we could say but here it's uncountable.
也许我们可以说，但在这里它是不可数的。
It will all work out just fine that means don't worry about it.
一切都会好起来的，这意味着不用担心。
Just wait a little while and everything will be OK.
稍等片刻，一切都会好起来的。
Everything will be OK all right.
一切都会好起来的。
So some is in particular a very very useful quanta fire just like a lot.
所以有些是特别非常有用的量子火，就像很多一样。
Remember these two.
记住这两个。
If you don't remember anything else about this lesson.
如果你不记得这节课的其他内容。